

# Sameer Kamran

Nationality: Pakistani

**(**+49) 1774052203

Date of birth: 26/11/1995

**Gender:** Male

**Email address:** me@sameerkamran.com

**Website:** sameerkamran.com

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sameer-kamran-dev/

• Address: Koblenzer Str. 236, 56073 Koblenz (Germany)

#### **ABOUT ME**

Sameer is an Intermediate level Software Engineer, who has experience of around 3 years in software industry in Pakistan. Recently relocated to Koblenz, Germany. Currently studying Masters Web & Data Science from University of Koblenz. Looking for new opportunities to showcase my skills and to learn more in my field.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Dot Net / Angular Developer**

**Boltech Solutions** [ 01/06/2019 - 13/10/2020 ]

Address: Lahore (Pakistan)

City: Lahore

Country: Pakistan

My responsibilities here, were to design databases, software architecture, and direct communication with clients.

- Worked on Tax Management System for Government of Malawi, Africa (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, AutoMapper, Autofac, Angular 6, Angular Material, PrimeNg)
- Worked on GYM Management System for UFC Gym International (.Net Core 3.0, MySQL, SignalR, AutoMapper, Audofac, Angular 8, Angular Material, ZKTeco Access Gates Integration)
- Worked on Employee Service Catalogue & Digital Approvals System for Exceed IT Services (ExpressJS, Mongoose, MongoDB, Angular 7)

## **Software Engineer**

**Codility Solutions** [ 01/03/2018 – 01/06/2019 ]

Address: Lahore (Pakistan)

City: Lahore

**Country:** Pakistan

Developed multiple Software/Solutions for clients around the world, was part of the requirement gathering team as well.

- Worked on Purchase Order Management Web Application (.Net Core 2.1 WebApi, SQL Server, .Net MVC5, Knockout/S, Vanilla/S, SQL Server)
- Worked on Inventory/Point-of-Sale Desktop Application (WPF, SQLite, MvvmCross, DevExpress)
- Worked on Office Management System. Attendance/Task Management (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, ZKTeco Biometric Integration)

## .Net Developer (Internship)

**Inseparable Technology Pvt. Ltd.** [ 01/04/2017 – 15/07/2017 ]

Address: Lahore (Pakistan)

City: Lahore

Country: Pakistan

Did my internship for around 3 months, Learnt a lot about how development cycle actually works.

• Worked on an Ecommerce Store (.Net MVC5, SQL Server, SignalR, OAuth, Social Media Integration)

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

#### **Masters Web & Data Science**

Universität Koblenz · Landau [ 15/10/2020 – Current ]

Address: Universitätsstraße 1, 56070 Koblenz (Germany)

#### **BS Information Technology**

**University of the Punjab** [ 07/10/2013 - 12/12/2017 ]

Address: Lahore (Pakistan)

Basic Programming, Data Structure and Algorithms, Networking e.t.c

## **Certified .Net Specialist**

**E-Venture Solutions** [ 02/03/2017 - 02/07/2017 ]

Address: Lahore (Pakistan)

Asp .Net MVC5,C#,Bootstrap,JQuery

#### **Intermediate**

**Govt. College of Science** [ 01/07/2011 - 03/04/2013 ]

Address: Lahore (Pakistan)

English, Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics

#### **Matriculation**

**Unique High School** [ 01/06/2009 - 01/06/2011 ]

Address: Lahore (Pakistan)

English, Computer Science, Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s):

Urdu

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING C2 READING C1 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1** 

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

Management tools (JIRA, Confluence) / Microsoft Office / Collaboration (Teams, Slack, Zoom, Webex, Miro u.a.) / Asana

#### **ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS**

#### **Organisational skills**

Lead some web based projects my self in a team of 3 persons.

#### **COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

### **Communication and interpersonal skills**

Well for sometime i worked in a call center from there I gained alot of good speaking and listening skills.

#### **JOB-RELATED SKILLS**

#### Job-related skills

.Net Core 2.x, 3.x. Asp .Net MVC5, Angular 2+, ReactJS, NodeJS, GIT, Agile Development, Bootstrap, JQuery, KnockoutJS